Kevin Warde

Atlanta, Georgia · 404.664.5431 · e-mail: kevinwarde@gmail.com

OVERVIEW

<u>Strong Skills & Experience:</u> **20 years of experience in commercialization & strategy development across technology, fintech & payments companies**

- · Specialist skill set combining growth & product strategy in the context of emerging technologies into a unique approach spanning realistic strategy evaluation & development linked to execution road mapping & commercialization stages
- · Strong cross-functional foundation with deep experience in product, innovation, channel & partners

<u>Strong Achievements:</u> High-impact results - **increased company revenue by 18%+ and net income by 35%+**Two President's Awards for **innovation Employee of the Year** Honor Society

<u>Strong Technology Experience:</u> e-commerce, payments, mobile, web and distributed software applications, web marketing, point of sale, kiosks, hardware

Strong Education: MBA with Honors - Emory's Goizueta Business School · BS in Engineering

CAREER EXPERIENCE

Head of Strategy, North America, Vice President

Elavon, subsidiary of US Bank (payment technology & processing)

Atlanta 2011-Present

Head of Strategy for North America acting as **lead strategic adviser to the country leaders of four countries** covering \$1+ B in revenues. Developed country-level & functional strategies spanning many business aspects.

- Led numerous global & functional strategies through a **staged growth framework** spanning evaluation, collaborative plan development, strategic road mapping & execution checkpoints
- Developed global Product Strategy spanning entire product scope, from legacy to over the horizon products incorporating **evaluation & commercialization of emerging technologies** (mobile, e-commerce, integration technologies and new payment methods)
- Developed **channel & sales force strategies** spanning channel modernization (digital paths to customers), evolving channel management practices, & salesforce transformation
- Developed **global acquisition & partnership strategy** focusing on technology-oriented targets as a part of an e-commerce and payments technology strategy
- Led country-level & segment strategies in North & Latin America, & Europe
- Awarded Gold-Shield Award for outstanding collaboration

Strategy/ Corporate Development - Director

Purchasing Power - Entrepreneur Top 500 (fintech/ e-commerce) Atlanta 2007–2010 Responsible for **strategic growth initiatives** (via partners, channel and new products) in a first-mover company in a niche market - \$140 M, 40% growth rate.

- Increased company revenue by 18%+ and net income by 35%+, totaling \$20+M in previous 18 months
- Growth initiatives included new product development, value-added strategy (Symantec), new venture development (Intel), new channel development (Dell), and new brand concept
- Exceptional value proposition development: Strong evaluation abilities of the multiple perspectives of value creation customer, product/competitive positioning, brand alignment, financial, and leverage of the company's competencies
- Strong ability to quickly develop strategic concepts into results: Disciplined planning process with a strategic
 pipeline and Go/No-Go Decision gateways to create a focus on high-impact concepts; business case
 development; strong evaluation skills of cross-functional capabilities and constraints to ensure successful
 execution of strategic goals
- Led cross-functional execution teams to successful launches with a strong ability to build executive and department support
- Employee of the Year; President's Award for Innovation

General Manager

Southwest Spine & Sport (family medical practice startup)

Fort Myers / Atlanta 2004 - 2006

Launched and managed family's medical practice (from initial founding to marketing, expansion plans, process development, and finances) growing from \$0 to \$1.5M and two offices.

Product Launch, Development & Marketing; Consulting Program Manager; International Planning

Radiant Systems (software and hardware technology for retailers)

Atlanta 1998-2003

Implemented strategies that led the company into new markets and products for its **internet platform & applications**. This cross-functional position encompassed **strategic and partner development**, sales and product strategy.

- Led and closed two strategic firsts first client on a new product and first entry into a new segment
- Comprehensive role in new market entry:
 - from evaluation of new markets and products, and business case development
 - o to leading teams for conceptual design and market requirements of new products
 - to contract negotiation with deal sizes in the \$ million+ range
- Led cross-functional team to implement the first customer-ordering kiosk based on a new platform
- · Led product design, prototype and launch of a new kiosk pilot that led to a \$15+ million deal
- Developed new branding and product positioning for the product portfolio

Project Manager - Engineering

Law Engineering (engineering consulting)

Miami & Atlanta 1993-1997

Managed consulting engineering projects, supervising up to 15 engineers and contractors per project.

- President's Award for innovation and teamwork
- Promoted to Project Manager within two years, normally a four plus year progression

EDUCATION

Emory University - Goizueta Business School, MBA

Atlanta 1999

1993

- National Honor Society (Beta Gamma Sigma) graduated in the Top 10%
- Concentration in Strategic Planning with coursework in technology impacts to markets and growth strategies

University of Florida, Bachelor of Science in Engineering

Gainesville, Florida

Coached local youth teams in soccer, basketball and football

Professional Development

- Constantly evolving growth strategy framework combining concepts from experiences, Zook's Beyond the Core, Crossing the Chasm, Stage Gate, and leverage concepts from Systems Dynamics
- New Product/Market Entry: Crossing the Chasm, minimum viable product & evolution, Blue Ocean, etc.
- Complex Sales Strategic Selling, Managing the Complex Sale
- Project Management Company-sponsored coursework